# **Hugo Malzieux**

hmalzieux@gmail.com | 0221964151 | +33631981343 | https://linkedin.com/in/hugo-malzieux

## **Personal Statement**

I am a web developer, specialized in React and NestJS. I enjoy working with all types of JavaScript/Typescript technologies, whether frontend or backend. I'm looking forward to collaborate on innovative projects, where I can bring my skills and knowledge to the table.

## **Work Experiences**

#### HABX

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER | OCT 2022 - MAY 2023

- Frontend development of a platform for real estate agents and construction agencies, designed to maximize the customer value, by providing future residents the opportunity to influence the design of their future home.
- I worked on the development of an open-source Design System, build with React and Styled Component library (<a href="https://habx.github.io/concrete-docs">https://habx.github.io/concrete-docs</a>).

#### **WAYZR**

## CO-FOUNDER & FULLSTACK DEVELOPER | OCT 2021 - OCT 2022

I co-founded a platform to create business collaboration between Brands and Artists, which provides multiple services such as collaboration contract, copywriting or publicity.

- I developed the backend of the SaaS platform: I designed the architecture with the framework NestJS, I created databases with PostgreSQL and Prisma as ORM. I Set up SSO/OAuth authentications with several providers (Google, Facebook...) with PassportJS.
- I developed Frontend apps for each type of user (Brand/Artist) with Nx monorepo: I Built the User Experience with ReactJS and Redux. I integrated the UI designs done with Figma, by using the framework Tailwind CSS. I added an Adding a direct messaging feature with Web Socket (Socket.io).
- I also developed a NextJS app for the landing page of the platform and the onboarding for user, which redirect on the right React app corresponding to the user type.
- I developed platform with React and Redux to manage partnerships and commissions for E-commerce website (WooCommerce, Shopify).

## **RAKUTEN DX**

## **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER | OCT 2020 - OCT 2021**

I developed a no-code SaaS platform for the creation of native mobile applications, intended for Designers. The backend was built in NestJS, Angular for the frontend (with NgRX, RxJS) and a React integration to visualize the mobile app.

## **ALTRAN**

#### **CONSULTANT ENGINEER | JUL 2018 - OCT 2020**

At Altran, I worked on several projects concerning different business sectors.

- I worked as Frontend consultant for a web application in medical analysis, we used Angular, Angular Material, NgRX, RxJS
- I worked as Backend consultant on a software, which provided feedback on experience of mechanical parts for helicopters, we used Java 11 with SpringBoot

## **Education**

## MASTER'S DEGREE | 2016 - 2018 | UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE, MONTPELLIER

Architecture, Software and Web Engineering

## BACHELOR'S DEGREE | 2013 - 2016 | UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE, MONTPELLIER

Architecture, Software and Web Engineering

## **Skills & Abilities**

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES, SOFTWARES, FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES

React (fluent); NestJS (fluent); Node.js (proficient); NextJS (proficient); Nx (proficient); TailwindCSS (fluent); Styled-component (fluent); scss (fluent); React Native (proficient); Ionic (basic); Angular (fluent); Jira (fluent); Redux (fluent); NgRx (fluent); RxJs (fluent); Figma (fluent); Java (proficient); Junit (proficient);

#### **LANGUAGES**

French (native); English (fluent); Spanish (basic);